Will Jutsum

Website: tweededbadger.com
E-Mail: will@tweededbadger.com

LinkedIn: goo.gl/xykmy0

GitHub: github.com/TweededBadger



A freelance Creative Technologist with 10 years experience working in digital marketing agencies, I have a breadth of knowledge in multiple platforms, technologies & APIs.

Adaptable to many situations, I am just as happy chairing brainstorming meetings or liaising with clients as I am knee deep in code.

Technical Skills Overview

HTML5/CSS - Comfortable building responsive layouts from scratch or using a framework such as Bootstrap. I have a preference for LESS for CSS preprocessing.

Javascript - Experience with a variety of JS frameworks & libraries (jQuery, Knockout, Angular, GSAP, CreateJS), as well as vanilla JS.

Unity 3D / C# - I have developed a number of crossplatform mobile games using Unity, developed using C#. I have worked on a number of .Net websites.

PHP - I have built a number of sites & services using the Codeigniter framework, as well as experience with Wordpress.

Node.js - Another platform I admire for the speed in which projects can be developed, I have mostly used Node to build systems utilizing websockets.

Python - My language of choice for both personal & professional work due to the speed in which I can realise my ideas. I have used python to develop a number of tools for colleagues to solve problems & streamline workflows. A number of my projects utilise the Django web framework.

Arduino - I have a passion for electronics and have used the Arduino for a number of projects both in work and play from a web-enabled christmas tree to an automated thermostat for my office.

Source Control - Comfortable using both Git and SVN.

Software - My development IDEs of choice come from JetBrains. I am comfortable using the entire Adobe design suite as well as 3DS Max.

Work Experience

Fabric Worldwide

Senior Creative Technologist October 2014 - March 2015

I was brought in by Fabric to work on a large project for Heineken entitled "Cider Tales". Initially my role required me to provide technical expertise for what was a very complex project to ensure that the production phase ran as smoothly as possible. This meant working closely with the team and a number of external suppliers of assets. I built the entire main section of the website, and assisted 2 other team members building other sections of the site.

Technical Overview

- Complex text animations using Greensock Animation Platform & CreateJS
- An easily expendable website platform using RequireJS
- Control of HTML video to sync with Javascript animations

Caliber Interactive

Senior Developer

August 2014 - October 2014

I worked with Caliber to build a first of its kind web-based mobile internet speed test for their client Broadband Choices. The project required a significant amount of research & development, as the client required the test to be as accurate & fast as the Flash-based market leading speed test, Ookla. I developed both the front-end and back-end sections of the site. The site it live here: http://www.broadbandchoices.co.uk/mobile/speed-test

Technical Overview

- Responsive HTML & CSS (Using LESS preprocessor)
- AngularJS based front-end
- Full RESTful API for collecting and sharing test results written in Python utilising the Django framework
- SVG results map written in AngularJS, which provided the basis for this tutorial.

Work Experience (cont.)

Crab Creative

Acting Technical Director | May 2014 Senior Developer | 2008-2014

I was lucky enough to play an important role in the development of Crab in the 6 years I was there. The company had a staff of 5 when I joined, meaning that adapting to a number of roles was essential. As well as my development duties, there was a requirement to oversee the entire project lifecycle, as well as liaise with clients. Crab now has over 15 employees and works with a number of high profile brands such as Red or Dead, Warner Music and Drambuie.

Here is an overview of my role at Crab:

- Working on both web based and non web based projects using the technologies listed above.
- Research & Development of new technologies.
- Working closely with the Account Management team to provide technical input in the planning of all projects.
- Managing projects from inception to delivery.
- Establishing dialog with clients to help them understand the possibilities of technologies to fit their needs.
- Building systems to improve efficiency for both Crab & its clients.
- Managing a team of on and off site developers and chairing daily stand-up meetings.

Effective Marketing Systems

Front End Developer | 2005-2008

- Creation of Flash & HTML websites from pre-designed concepts.
- Communication with clients at all stages of website production.
- Attending meetings with prospective clients, to scope their requirements and inform them of services that the company could make available to them.

Education

1992-1999 - Sedbergh School, Cumbria. 5 A-Levels (4 As, 1 B) 1999-2002 - Computer Science - Edinburgh University, UK